# AYESHA KHALID

404.431.0363 | ayeshakhalid1@gmail.com | www.akhalid.org

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Economist and applied econometrician with 7 years of experience in data science, data mining and causal inference. Demonstrated ability to work with big data, manage simultaneous projects, and effectively communicate complex findings to technical and general audiences.

### **EDUCATION**

## UNIVERSITY OF OREGON, Eugene, OR

2015 - June 2020 Expected

Ph.D., Economics

Gerlof Homan Research Scholarship (awarded to 5 Ph.D. students each year), Best Econometrics Performance Award

## PORTLAND STATE UNIVERSITY, Portland, OR

2012 - 2014

M.S., Economics

Linda Hamilton Award (for student with highest GPA)

### LAHORE UNIVERSITY OF MANAGEMENT SCIENCES, Lahore, Pakistan

2002 - 2007

M.S., Economics; B.Sc., Economics

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## UNIVERSITY OF OREGON, DEPARTMENT OF ECONOMICS, OR

Sep 2015 – Present

Research projects

- Used advanced econometric techniques and modern software tools (R, Python) to estimate the causal impact of air pollution and climate change on student attendance and test scores, and produced policy recommendations
- Evaluated the treatment effect of a gender-targeted conditional cash transfer program on schooling outcomes
- Modeled key determinants of broadband provision using a dynamic discrete choice model
- Presented independent research projects at professional conferences

#### Teaching

- Independently taught 6 undergraduate economics courses, from freshmen to senior year level and ranging in size from 60-330 students, and prepared lectures and assessment material
- Managed teams of teaching assistants and graders in classes with 300+ students

### PORTLAND STATE UNIVERSITY, NORTHWEST ECONOMIC RESEARCH CENTER, OR

Mar 2013 – June 2014

Research Assistant

- Modeled determinants of spatial distribution of U.S. firms in China, and produced scientific peer-reviewed publication
- Estimated causal impact of being landlocked on Bolivia's economic growth and international trade
- Evaluated economic impact of carbon tax and the effect of property tax inequities on home sale prices in Oregon

## LAHORE UNIVERSITY OF MANAGEMENT SCIENCES & WORLD BANK, Pakistan

**Policy Researcher** 

Jan 2010 – March 2011

 Devised policy to increase competitiveness of industrial firms in an open economy environment for a World Bank funded project, and produced policy report for the Ministry of Industries and Production, Government of Pakistan

Independent Teaching Instructor

Sep 2007 - May 2010

Independently prepared and taught 12 undergraduate economics courses ranging in size from 75-150 students

### **SKILLS**

Software: R, Stata, Python, Matlab, SQL, JavaScript (Google Earth Engine), Excel (advanced), Latex Professional: Big Data Processing & Analysis, Presentations, Report Writing, Data Visualization

Languages: English (fluent), Urdu (native); Other: U.S. Permanent Resident